iconarchive.com 2018-12-22

# Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy was last updated on **24th May, 2018**

## Introduction

This statement discloses the privacy practices for this website **IconArchive.com**  
IconArchive.com respects the privacy and rights of its visitors. We do not collect personal identifiable data, and therefore protect user privacy. No effort is made to identify individuals without their knowledge. Please read the following to learn more about our privacy policy. 

## A Primer on Data Regulation

The General Data Protection Regulation is an EU law, taking effect from 25th May 2018. It broadens the definition of personal data to include anything unique to an individual. It also restates the requirements to have a solid legal basis for processing personal data and being transparent to data subjects (i.e. people) about what processing is taking place.  
Personal Data is therefore an EU term, including things like name, email address, but also unique cookie IDs and IP addresses

## Cookies

When you visit our site we use the following cookies: 

Cookie  
Name | Domain | Function | Class | Type | Expiry  
---|---|---|---|---|---  
**pid** | iconarchive.com | Cookie is used for the keyword suggestion feature. When you added several helpful keywords you are marked as a "good"/"helpful" user with your pid-Number in our database and your keyword suggestions are prioritized in future.  
Cookie is also used to track number of downloads. | Configuration | Persistent | 20 years  
**configuser** | iconarchive.com | Cookie is used for the search interface, resolution filter, color filter, category filter, etc. | Configuration | Session | Deleted after  
Browser Session  
**myicons** | iconarchive.com | Cookie is used to save your favourite icons. | Configuration | Persistent | 3 years  
**myiconssrc** | iconarchive.com | Cookie is used for the favourite icons feature and holds the data for the image previews. | Configuration | Persistent | 3 years  
  
## Cookies by Google Analytics (Visitor Stats)

We use **Google Analytics** to collect visitor information with the aim to optimize and improve our website.  
Google Analytics uses cookies to track visitor behaviour. For further details please visit the [privacy policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy) of Google Analytics. 

## Cookies by Advertising Networks

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, click [here](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/).  
We use the following ad networks: 

  1. **Google Adsense** ([Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads))
  2. **BuySellAds** ([Privacy Policy](https://www.buysellads.com/about/privacy))  
 
  3. **Exponential Interactive** ([Privacy Policy](http://exponential.com/privacy/))  
Exponential Interactive, Inc, as our partner, have a legitimate interest to collect and profile personal data in the form of IP address and cookie ID from users on our website in order to provide targeted online advertising and ad measurement. For more details including opt-out requests, access requests or complaints, please review their [privacy policy](http://exponential.com/privacy/) or contact their data protection officer via [privacy@exponential.com](mailto:privacy@exponential.com). 

## Disable Cookies

It is possible to disable cookies, but this will limit your browsing experience.  
Without cookies you can't use the "My Favorite icons" function or the "Latest icons" function on IconArchive.com.  
First (and easy) method: In your browser open a new "Incognito" or "Private mode" window for better privacy.  
No tracking is done on your computer and only nondurable session cookies are used.  
Second method: Disable Cookies completely in the Preferences of your browser.  
Disabling cookies depends on your browser and opererating system, so please do a google search like this one:  
"Disable cookies in Chrome on Windows" or  
"Disable cookies in Safari on iPhone"  

## Links to external sites

This site contains links to other sites.  
IconArchive.com is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. 

If you have any additional questions or concerns about this policy, please feel free to contact us.
